HARSHIT GUPTA

harshit.gupta.cor@gmail.com

BM 4.134, EPFL, Lausanne CH-1015, Switzerland

Homepage

Google Scholar

CURRENT RESEARCH FOCUS

My research is aimed at designing mathematically backed deep-learning algorithms for solving inverse problems in imaging. I am interested in the modalities of Cryo Electron Microscopy (Cryo-EM), Computational Tomography (CT), and Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI).

EDUCATION

July 2015 - September 2020 École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: "From Classical to Unsupervised-Deep-Learning Methods

for Solving Inverse Problems in Imaging".

Advisor: Prof. Michael Unser

July 2011 - May 2015

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Guwahati, India

B. Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

July 2014 - May 2015 Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Guwahati, India

Bachelor Thesis Project

Topic: "Blind Image Quality Assessment"

Advisor: Prof. Kannan Karthik

May 2014 - July 2014 École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland

Research Internship

Topic: "Interpolation using Derivatives"

Advisor: Prof. Michael Unser

May 2013 - July 2013 Indian Institute of Science (IISc), Bangalore, India

Research Internship

Topic: "Building a MATLAB GUI on Optic Disk

Localization using ℓ_1 -minimization"

Advisor: Prof. Chandra Sekhar Seelamantula

PUBLICATIONS

Preprints

- 8. **Gupta H***, McCann M T*, Donati L, Unser M, "CryoGAN: A New Reconstruction Paradigm for Single-particle Cryo-EM Via Deep Adversarial Learning," bioRxiv 2020.03.20.001016, March <u>2020</u>. *Co-first authors. [PDF]
- 7. Jin K H*, **Gupta H***, Yerly J, Stuber M, Unser M, "Time-Dependent Deep Image Prior for Dynamic MRI," IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, in Revision. *Co-first authors. [PDF]

Journals

- Aziznejad S, Gupta H, Campos J, Unser M, "Deep Neural Networks with Trainable Activations and Controlled Lipschitz Constant," IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, vol. 68, pp. 4688 - 4699, August 2020.
- 5. Yang F, Pham T, **Gupta H**, Unser M, Ma J, "Deep-learning projector for optical diffraction tomography," Optics Express, vol. 28(3), pp. 3905-3921, February 2020. [PDF]
- 4. Debarre T, Fageot J, **Gupta H**, Unser M, "B-spline-based exact discretization of continuous-domain inverse problems with generalized TV regularization," IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, vol. 65(7), pp.4457-4470, March 2019. [PDF]
- 3. **Gupta H**, Jin K H, Nguyen H Q, McCann M T, Unser M, "CNN-based projected gradient descent for consistent CT image reconstruction," IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 37(6), pp. 1440-1453, May 2018.
- Gupta H, Fageot J, Unser M, "Continuous-domain solutions of linear inverse problems with Tikhonov versus generalized TV regularization," IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, vol. 66(17), pp. 4670-4684, July 2018.
- 1. Unser M, Fageot J, **Gupta H**, "Representer Theorems for Sparsity-Promoting ℓ_1 Regularization," IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, vol. 62(9), pp. 5167-5180, August 2016. [PDF]

Conference and Workshop Proceedings

- Gupta H, Phan T H, Yoo J, Unser M, "Multi-CryoGAN: Reconstruction of continuous conformations in Cryo-EM using Generative Adversarial Networks," Proc. European Conference on Computer Vision Workshops (ECCVW <u>2020</u>) (Online, August 23-28), in press.
- 3. Debarre T, Fageot J, **Gupta H**, Unser M, "Solving Continuous-domain Problems Exactly with Multiresolution B-splines," Proc. IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP <u>2019</u>) (Brighton, UK, May 12-17), pp. 5122-5126. [PDF]
- Gupta H, Schmitter D, Uhlmann V, Unser M, "General surface energy for spinal cord and aorta segmentation," IEEE Proc. International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI <u>2017</u>), (Sydney, Australia, April 18-21), pp. 319-322.
- 1. Uhlmann V, Fageot J, **Gupta H**, Unser M, "Statistical optimality of Hermite splines," Proc. International Conference on Sampling Theory and Applications (SampTA <u>2015</u>), (Washington, DC, US, May 25-29), pp. 226-230. [PDF]

TEACHING EXPERIENCES

September 2015 - August 2020 Teaching Assistant at EPFL

Image Processing I - Autumn 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019 Image Processing II - Spring 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020

September 2019 - February 2019 Supervisor for Master Semester Project

Student: Huy Thong, EPFL

Topic: "Reconstructing multiple-conformations of particles in Cryo-Electron Microscopy with deep learning"

January 2019 - June 2019 Co-supervisor for Master Semester Project

Student: Huy Thong, EPFL

Topic: "Implementing Deep-learning-based

iterative algorithm to solve inverse problem of MRI"

January 2019 - June 2019 Supervisor for Master Semester Project

Student: Joaquim Campos, EPFL

Topic: "Learning Spline-based activations for very deep learning"

September 2018 - February 2019 Co-supervisor for Master Thesis

Student: Matthieu Broisin, EPFL in collaboration with MIT, USA Topic: "Segmentation of images using a Deep-Learning-based approach"

April 2017 - Septmeber 2017 Co-supervisor for Master Thesis

Student: Thomas Debarre, ENS Paris Saclay, Cachan, France Topic: "B-spline-based exact discretization of continuous-domain inverse problems with generalized TV regularization"

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, Java, C, C++

Libraries PyTorch, MatConvNet Softwares ImageJ, Fiji, Chimera

HONOURS

- Selected for II round of Texas Instruments Innovation Challenge: India Analog Design Contest 2014.
- Selected in national Top-30 in Manthan, CAG, 2014, among more than 150 teams.
- Placed among top 0.5% in 2011 IIT-Joint Entrance Exam (to enroll in undergraduate program) given by 500,000 students.
- Placed among National Top 1% in National Standard Examination in Physics, 2010-11, organized by Indian Association of Physics Teachers.
- Secured AIR-171 in National Level Science Talent Search Examination, 2009.
- Secured 3rd position in SBM Inter School Science and Environment Quiz, 2008.
- Awarded the Talent Scholarship Award by Saraswati Siksha Sansthan, 2008.